// creating an array and passing the number, questions, options, and answers
let questions = [
    {
    numb: 1,
    question: "Refracting telescopes always contain which one of the following ?",
    answer: "lenses",
    options: [
      "mirrors",
      "lenses",
      "television systems",
      "film"
    ]
  },
    {
    numb: 2,
    question: "A comet's tail points in which direction ?",
    answer: "away from the sun",
    options: [
      "toward the sun",
      "toward the earth",
      "behind the comet in its orbit",
      "away from the sun"
    ]
  },
    {
    numb: 3,
    question: "Spectral line splitting due to the influence of magnetic fields is called :",
    answer: "Zeeman Effect",
    options: [
      "Boltzmann Effect",
      "Zeeman Effect",
      "Planck Effect",
      "Zanstra's Effect"
    ]
  },
    {
    numb: 4,
    question: "Beads of light visible around the rim of the moon at the beginning and end of a total solar eclipse are called :",
    answer: "Baily's Beads",
    options: [
      "Lunar Beads",
      "Solar Beads",
      "Baily's Beads",
      "Rim Beads"
    ]
  },
    {
    numb: 5,
    question: "Whereas latitude and longitude are the coordinates of places on earth, the coordinates used for star locations are two of the following.",
    answer: "right ascension and declination",
    options: [
      "right ascension and altitude",
      "altitude and declination",
      "declination and polar angle",
      "right ascension and declination"
    ]
  },
  
   {
     numb: 6,
     question: "The 2.7 Kelvin cosmic background radiation is concentrated in the :",
     answer: "radio wavelengths",
    options: [
       "radio wavelengths",
       "infrared",
       "visible",
       "ultraviolet"
     ]
   },
   
   {
      numb: 7,
     question: "If you were watching a star collapsing to form a black hole, the light would disappear because it :",
     answer: "is strongly redshifted",
    options: [
       "is strongly blueshifted",
       "its color suddenly becomes black",
       "is strongly redshifted",
       "none of the above"
     ]
   },
   { numb: 8,
     question: "In which spectral region is it possible for astronomers to observe through clouds?",
     answer: "radio",
    options: [
       "visual",
       "radio",
       "ultraviolet",
       "x-ray"
     ]
   },
   {
   numb: 9,
     question: "The Magellanic Clouds are",
     answer: "irregular galaxies",
    options: [
       "irregular galaxies",
       "spiral galaxies",
       "elliptical galaxies",
       "large clouds of gas and dust"
     ]
   },
   {
   numb: 10,
     question: "The VISUAL aurora consists of luminous arcs, rays or bands in the night sky, usually confined to high latitudes and located in the :",
     answer: "ionosphere",
    options: [
       "troposphere",
       "stratosphere",
       "ozonosphere",
       "ionosphere"
     ]
   },
];